How could this happen?
怎么会发生这种事？
Your Highness.
大人
LONGING
（恋）
May I ask what you are doing here all alone?
您一个人在这里做什么呢？大人
Well…
那个…
I wanted to get some fresh air after my reading,
我书读到一半觉得心烦意乱
so I came out for a walk.
才会出来散散步
Does this belong to you?
这是您的吗？
What?
什么？
Yes. That's mine.
对 那是我的
Only commoners play with something like this.
这是平民小孩在玩的东西
How did you get this?
怎么会在您手上？
There you are, my lord.
原来你在这里啊 大监
So tell me.
好
Were you able to see her off?
好好送走那个孩子了吗？
Yes, my lord.
是的 大监
I suggest you go back to your quarters.
请回寝殿吧
His Majesty made it clear that you were to stay in your quarters.
殿下已下令不许您 离开世孙殿一步 不是吗？
Wait.
等等
Yes?
是？
Why are you in such a hurry?
您为何急急忙忙的？
You should take what's yours.
这您要拿回去啊
Right.
对
Okay.
好
Hey, you're not supposed to be here.
我说 你怎么能待在这里？
We must go back, Your Highness.
您怎么会在这里呢？
I have been looking all over for you.
小的找您找了好久 大人
Escort him to his quarters now.
尽快服侍世孙回寝殿
He is not to leave his room today.
尤其是今日 更不该让他四处乱跑
-Do you understand? -Pardon?
-听懂了吗？ -什么？
I'm sorry.
对不起
I was really going to come back right after I gave him these.
我真的想把这个拿给他之后 就马上赶回来
I'll tell on you once His Highness returns.
等大人回来 我会把一切都告诉他
I'll tell him how you snuck out when you were supposed to stay inside.
都要你乖乖待在寝殿了 你却偷溜出去
Hey, Bok-dong.
喂 福童
Bok-dong.
福童
Mother, I wasn't informed that you would be stopping by.
母后 怎么没先通知一声就过来？
Who else knows about this?
还有谁知道这件事？
Pardon? What do you mean?
什么？您这是什么意思？
That this child here
这个孩子
swapped clothes with my son.
跟世孙换装这件事
Who else knows about this?
还有谁知道？
Please spare us.
请娘娘饶命
The Prince, Dam-i, and I are the only ones who know.
只有世孙大人、我和垣 三个人知道而已
Please forgive me. I was just following the Prince's order.
小的犯了死罪 我只是遵从世孙大人之命…
As of this moment, you are…
从此刻起
the Prince.
就是世孙
You…
绝对
cannot speak of this to anyone.
不能把实情告诉任何人
You have to take this secret to the grave.
直到你死那天都不能让别人知道
Do you understand me?
听懂我的话了吗？
EPISODE 2
第 2 集
My dear Prince…
世孙大人
Where are you going, Your Highness?
您要去哪里啊？大人
Your Highness.
大人！
Your Highness, what are you going to do?
大人 您到底想做什么？
I will go back to where I belong.
我要回到我原本的位置
It's the Crown Princess.
是嫔宫娘娘
It is my understanding that you have the girl's body.
听说你把孩子的尸首带回来了
I am a parent who lost her daughter.
我是个把孩子深埋在心中的娘
Nothing can stop me now.
现在我还有什么事做不出来？
-I must see her body. -Why?
-我得看看她 -为什么？
Do you not trust your man, Jung Seok-jo?
你是信不过郑析助吗？
I was under the impression that
只要爹下令
he wouldn't hesitate to kill even my child if you ordered him to do so.
他甚至能毫不犹豫地斩杀我的家人
You can take her with you if that will help you feel reassured.
若你还是不放心 就直接带走她吧
I brought her into the world. So naturally,
既然她是我女儿
So you can send her off
那就由你亲手
yourself.
送走她吧
No parent
不管是何种父母
wants to hurt their child.
都没有人愿意伤害自己的孩子
Everything I am doing is for you and our family's sake.
这一切都是为了你和整个家族
Find it in your heart to let this go.
你不要太埋怨我
Go ahead.
过去吧
-I-wol, wait up. -Wait up.
-二月 一起走嘛 -一起走嘛
What took you so long? I thought you left without me.
你们怎么这么慢？ 我还以为你们先走了
-Excuse me. -Goodness.
-等一下 -吓我一跳
Are you I-wol?
你就是二月吗？
Do you know me?
你认识我吗？
Of course. Don't you work with Dam-i?
当然啊 你是跟垣 一起工作的伙伴对吧？
Can you give this to Dam-i when you go back?
你回去时能帮我把这转交给垣吗？
My name is Jung Ji-un. Wait, no. Tell her "Zuo Zhuan." Then, she'll know.
我是郑至韵
I'm sorry I can't do that.
我没办法帮这个忙
I need your help. I want to give it to her in person,
拜托你了 虽然我想亲手交给她
but I can't go inside.
但我无法进宫
Can you please give this letter to her?
只要帮我转交这封信就好 可以吗？
It's not that. Dam-i isn't at the palace anymore.
不是那样的
She's not at the palace?
她不在宫中？
She disappeared.
她消失了
And no one knows where she went either.
而且没有人知道她的下落
What do you mean?
那是什么意思？
She left to attend the banquet for the elderly,
她因为敬老宴出宫之后
but never came back.
就没有再回来了
No one including the court ladies and maids
尚宫娘娘和姮娥都说
has seen her.
没见到她
It's not like she has a place to go outside the palace.
她明明出宫之后就无处可去
Father.
爹
Were you at the palace?
你今天去了王宫那边吗？
Yes.
对
I wanted to see my friend.
我有个一定要见到的人
Are you talking about the court maid?
是那个宫女吗？
Father, I have a favor to ask you.
爹 我有件事想拜托你
The next time you are at the palace, could you ask around about my friend?
如果你有进宫
No one has seen her after the banquet for the elderly.
听说她出宫参加敬老宴后就不见人影
You might have better luck finding her as you are an inspector.
你身为司宪府的监察 可能有办法打听到
Do you think tracking down a mere maid is my job?
你以为司宪府的工作是在追查 区区一个宫女的下落吗？
-That's not what I meant. -Never…
-我不是那个意思… -再也
bring her up in front of me again. Do you understand?
别在我面前提起她的事 听懂了吗？
Did you not eat anything all day?
你一整天都没吃东西吗？
Eat.
快吃
Eat even if rice tastes like sand in your mouth.
即使饭如沙粒般难以下咽也要吞下去
And drink water even if it tastes like
即使水尝起来像苦药般
bitter medicine.
也要隐忍着喝下去
I don't want to.
我不要
I hate everything.
我讨厌这一切
If you give up now,
若你就此放弃
it will mean death for everyone around you.
在场的每个人都难逃一死
Including you and me.
不管是你还是我
Everyone.
所有人都会死
Are you awake?
您起床了吗？
Let us bring in water for your face.
小的要送盥洗的水进去
Starting now,
往后有关世孙殿的事
Court Lady Kim and Eunuch Hong will be taking care of you.
都会由金尚宫和洪内官一手包办
So do not worry.
你不必太担心
-Maids will bring water and help you wash -Please stop.
早上一起床
in the morning.
帮你盥洗
You don't have to do a thing.
你什么都不用做
-Let the maids handle everything. -Your Highness.
-把一切交给宫女们打理 -大人
Your schedule is fairly simple.
世孙的日常作息很单纯
Every morning, you will go to the King's quarters
每日早晨至大殿和交泰殿
as well as the Queen's quarters to offer your greetings.
向殿下和中殿娘娘请安
And then, you will come to our quarters to say hello to the Crown Prince and me.
尔后再至东宫殿向邸下和我问安即可
-Oh, my back. -The Prince is here.
-唉唷 我的腰 -世孙大人驾到
I was concerned when I heard you weren't feeling well for a while.
之前听闻你的身体微恙 本宫还很担心呢
Are you feeling better now?
现在都痊愈了吗？
Yes. I am sorry to have caused you to worry.
是的 孙儿很抱歉让您担心了
Is it because you've been sick recently?
是因为身体还很虚弱吗？
You don't sound as strong as before.
总觉得你的声音 不如以往那般铿锵有力
No, Your Majesty. I am perfectly fine.
不是的 孙儿真的没有大碍
This isn't good.
这样不行
I will have one of my people to deliver some tonics to get your energy up.
本宫会吩咐药房送养身的汤药过去
Make sure to drink it every day.
别忘了要按时服用
Yes, Your Majesty.
是 中殿娘娘
It's time for the morning assembly.
很快就要进行常参了
This is enough for morning greetings. You may all leave now.
问安就到此为止
I keep stepping on my robe as it is too long.
衣服太长了 害我一直绊到
And this is too big for my head.
头冠也太大了
I will get them altered today.
小的会在今日全数修改好
No, not there. It's that way.
不是往那边 而是另一边
The other way around.
是反方向才对
Your Highness, I have the herbal tonics from the Queen.
大人 这是从中宫殿送来的汤药
It is hot. So please be careful.
药很烫 请小心服用
Hot!
好烫
I'm sorry. It's my fault.
对不起 我不小心打翻了
Oh, no.
这该怎么办？
I'm sorry, Your Highness. I'll go and bring another bowl.
小的惶恐 小的马上再端一碗过来
Are you all right? Gosh, it's my fault.
你没事吧？都是我害的
No. I'm all right.
您别这么说 小的没事
Don't worry about this.
现在这个重要吗？
Bok-dong.
福童
Did you ask for me?
您找小的吗？
Get some ointment from the royal pharmacy.
吩咐内药房拿点外伤药过来
-Pardon? -Hurry.
-什么？ -快去啊
Your Highness.
大人
Please forgive me. It was my mistake.
请娘娘赐死 这都是因为小的失手
You may all leave.
全都退下
The cut was deep. Please call a physician for her.
她手上的伤口很深 请叫医员替她治疗
There's no need.
没那个必要
It is not your place to worry about her even if her finger is wounded or severed.
不管她的手是被划伤还是手指断了
She was hurt because of me because I dropped the bowl.
她是因为我才受伤的 因为我没拿好碗…
No.
不
It was her fault.
是她失手了
So you are never to apologize.
所以你绝对不要道歉
You are not to worry about other people.
你没必要在意其他人
Think only about yourself.
你只要想着自己就好
You are not to care about what others think of you.
你也不需要在意其他人对你的观感
That's what it means…
世孙…
to be the Prince.
就是这样的人
There's no need to show respect to others
无须跟其他人低头
or feel bad for them.
也不必介意他们
The only people you will show respect to
你该低头尊敬的人
are the King and the Crown Prince.
就只有殿下和邸下而已
Do you understand that?
听懂了吗？
But…
不过
Why must I do that?
为何我非要那么做不可？
That's not how I want to live.
我不想成为那样的人
It is only fair that
只要我做错事
I apologize to whoever deserves my apology when I'm at fault.
无论是谁 我都认为自己 应该跟对方道歉
No matter what my title may be.
即便我的身份是世孙大人
They must know their place.
你得让他们觉得你难以亲近
Make them fear you.
让他们畏惧你
So don't let them get close to you.
因此要让他们无法靠近你
Only then will you survive.
这样你才能活下去
Even your shoulders.
要跟肩膀呈一直线才对
And your stance must be wider.
步幅要往这边再跨大一点
Who are you?
你是谁？
It's me, Hyun.
是我 显
Hyun?
显？
Are you training together?
两位又展开武术对决了啊？
No. Does this look like training to you?
才不是呢 你觉得这像在对练吗？
As the Prince's good cousin, Prince Jaeun, is here,
既然世孙大人 最亲近的王兄者隐君来了
I will bring some refreshments right away.
小的会尽快去端茶点过来
No. That won't be necessary.
不用了 没那个必要
Sorry. I may have been out of line with my prank.
对不起 是我玩笑开过头了 王兄
By the way, what brings you here?
不过你怎么会来这里？
Isn't it obvious why I'm here?
这还用问？
Your birthday is around the corner.
你的生辰马上就要到了啊
So I came to ask you what you would like
所以我来问你这次想收到什么礼物
for your birthday.
顺便进宫一趟
My birthday?
我的生辰？
He's the brother of the King and the son of Queen Consort An,
这位是主上殿下的兄弟 也是惠嫔安氏之子
Lord Hyeonun.
贤安君大监
Congratulations, Your Highness.
微臣恭贺您生辰大喜 世孙大人
Lord Geumjeong of the Sinbin Kang clan.
这位是信嫔姜氏之子 锦诠君大监
They are the sons of the late Prince Dohyeon.
这两位是已故桃炫世子之子
They are Prince Wonsan and Prince Jaeun respectively.
前面这位是源山君 后面那位是者隐君
You met him before.
您之前见过他对吧？
Congratulations.
恭贺您生辰大喜
Thank you.
谢谢你 王兄
I hope you aren't confused today.
你今天没有搞混吧？
It's me, Hyun.
我是显
I was merely goofing around that day.
那天真的是我在闹着玩
What were you confused about?
您搞混了什么？
Hello.
您来了啊
Congratulations.
恭贺您生辰大喜
This fine weather today must be proof
今日的天气特别晴朗
that everything on Earth
看来这块土地上的万物
is celebrating your birthday.
都在欢庆着您的诞辰
Thank you.
谢谢
It is a true honor to witness
世孙居然已经这么大了
such magnificent growth in you.
让微臣不胜感激啊
It is my understanding that you have the girl's body.
听说你把孩子的尸首带回来了
Everything I am doing is for you and our family's sake.
这一切都是为了你和整个家族
Find it in your heart to let this go.
你不要太埋怨我
Please remember that
请别忘了朝鲜的命脉
the fate of Joseon solely relies on you.
都掌握在您的手上啊 世孙大人
I will devote my life to serving you
就像一直以来所做的那般
just as I have been doing so far.
微臣往后也会舍命来服侍您
Anxiety is getting to you.
您应该是太紧张了
You received enough guests for today. It's best we stop here now.
今天这样就够了 您不用再出去接受祝贺了
I can handle it.
我还承受得住
The son of Jung Seok-jo, an inspector at the Office of the Inspector General,
司宪府监察郑析助之子
asks to have an audience with you.
请求觐见
Let him in.
让他进来
My name is Jung Ji-un, the son of Inspector Jung Seok-jo
微臣是司宪府监察郑析助之子
at the Office of the Inspector General.
郑至韵
Thank you for granting me a private audience with you.
谢谢您让我进来问安
I heard that your birthday is today.
微臣耳闻今日是您的诞辰
This may sound impudent,
不晓得这样会不会很冒昧
but after hearing about how excellent you are from a girl I knew,
但微臣从某个熟识的女孩口中
I wanted to meet you in person and wish you a happy birthday.
就想见您一面 亲自来祝贺您
From what she told me, you aren't authoritative
据她所描述的世孙大人形象
or arrogant,
并非是权威又威严
but a generous prince with a loving heart for his subjects.
而是一位仁慈对待百姓的宽厚君子
So ever since that day,
因此微臣
I have been hoping that one day, I would be able to serve you by your side.
从那天起便希望能随侍在大人身边
I'll soon be going to Ming for my studies.
微臣即将前往明国留学
And I will do my best there
日后当我重返此处时
to keep this promise to you and return as a subject you will be proud of.
我会努力成为不愧对今日约定的臣子
Please stay healthy until then.
恳请您在此之前务必要保重身体
Wait.
等等
Is the girl you mentioned
你所说的那个女孩
a girl named Dam-i?
是指垣吗？
Do you know her?
您知道有关她的事吗？
LONGING, NOT
（恋 不）
She told me to give these to you if I ever met you.
她说若是遇到你 就将这个转交给你
She told me they would help you stay strong when things get hard…
她说这能在你难受的时候 成为你的依靠
just like…
因为这对她来说
they had been helpful for her.
曾经也是她的依靠
By any chance,
请问
do you know where she went?
您知道她的下落吗？
I do not know.
我不晓得
Please let me escort you out.
现在就让小的带你出去吧
LONGING, WAIT
（恋 期）
Your Highness!
大人！
Aren't you the inspector who was looking for Dam-i that day?
您是上次来找垣的那位监察大人吧？
Please excuse me.
各位先走吧
Dam-i hasn't come back to the palace after the party for the elderly.
在敬老宴后垣就再也没回宫里
I was wondering if you met her that day.
小的想请问您那天是否有见到她
I'm not sure where she is. I hadn't seen her either.
这个嘛 我那天也没见到她
I see.
好的
Thank you for your time.
抱歉失礼了
Wait.
等等
Do you think you can help me?
你可以帮我一个忙吗？
Pardon?
什么？
I was actually looking for someone to help me.
我正好缺个人手
That girl…
她是…
Where are we going?
请问我们到底要去哪里？
The court maid will be looking for me.
姮娥会找我的
I should be going back to my post.
小的差不多该回岗位了
We're here.
我们到了
Why are you doing this? Please spare me.
您为何要这样？请饶了小的一命
I'm sorry. I'll make it quick.
抱歉 我会速战速决
No!
不可以！
No, Father. Please.
不可以这么做 爹 不行
What are you doing here?
你怎么会在这里？
Why are you trying to kill her?
你为何要杀她？
What did she do?
她做了什么？
This has nothing to do with you. Move.
这跟你无关 让开
Father!
爹！
Stop it, Father. Please!
请你不要这样 爹 求求你！
Move!
让开！
Father!
爹！
No!
不可以！
-Your Highness!
-大人 -世孙大人
Your Highness.
娘娘
Where is the Prince?
世孙呢？
No news yet. We searched the Prince's quarters,
还没找到 我们已经翻遍 世孙殿每个角落
but to no avail.
还是找不到她
We must find the child before anyone finds out.
得在其他人察觉之前尽快找到她
If something happens to that child too,
若连她都遭遇什么不测的话
I will never forgive myself.
我会死不瞑目的
Please do not worry. Everything will be all right.
请不用担心 不会有事的
No!
不可以！
No, Father. Please.
不可以这么做 爹 不行
Why are you trying to kill her? What did she do?
你为何要杀她？她做了什么？
This has nothing to do with you. Move.
这跟你无关 让开
Father!
爹！
Stop it, Father. Please!
请你不要这样 爹 求求你！
Move!
让开！
No!
不可以！
-Your Highness!
-大人！
Eunuch Hong, why don't you go there and check?
洪内官 你往那边
-Where are you?
-您在哪里啊？ -大人！
Your Highness!
世孙大人！
Where are you?
您在哪里啊？
Where are you, Your Highness?
您在哪里？
-Where are you? -Your Highness!
-您在哪里？ -大人！
Your Highness! Where are you?
您在哪里？
Your Highness!
世孙大人！
What are you doing here? Go and find the Prince now.
你到底在这里做什么？ 还不快去找世孙大人
-Your Highness!
-世孙大人！ -大人！
My heart breaks for the Prince.
世孙大人太可怜了
She must have been so scared.
她肯定十分恐惧不安
I wouldn't have lasted a day if I were in her shoes.
换作是我 连一天都撑不下去
The Prince's own grandfather had him killed.
杀害世孙大人的人居然是他外祖父
Being forced to live around those people
必须和那种人待在同个空间里
must have taken a toll on her.
她该有多难受啊？
But I couldn't do anything to lessen her burden.
而我却什么忙都帮不上
All I did was cry in front of her out of fear.
只会在她面前怕得直掉眼泪
You must be brave for the Prince.
为了世孙大人 你一定要坚强
The day the King finds out the truth,
这件事一旦被大殿得知
it will be the death of everyone.
每个人都难逃死劫
I'm here.
我在这
-Your Highness!
-大人
What on earth happened?
发生了什么事吗？
Everything is my fault.
全都是我害的
Everything.
一切都是
The Prince and I-wol died
世孙大人和二月
because of me.
都是被我害死的
Please stop crying.
不要哭了
This isn't your fault.
这不是您的错
Everything that's happened
这一切
is not your fault, Your Highness.
都不是您的错
The moon tonight is bright indeed.
月亮真是明亮皎洁啊
When I was pregnant with you, I had a dream.
怀着你的时候
A very big moon slid under my dress.
我梦见有一轮偌大的明月 落入我的裙摆里
And the moon split into two beautiful pearls.
尔后化为两颗明亮的珍珠
One of the pearls was your brother.
其中一颗就是你王兄
And the other pearl
另一颗
was probably you.
应该就是你了
I was happy…
我当时很幸福
when I had you and your brother.
怀着你们的时候
I was
我真的…
truly happy.
真的觉得很幸福
How come…
您为何
you are not scolding me?
不责骂我？
I ran away.
我都逃跑了
Why are you not scolding me?
您为何不教训我？
Because you came back.
你不是回来了吗？
You came back to your mother.
你重新回到我身边啦
I-wol…
二月她…
is dead.
死了
I cannot
杀了二月的
forgive the man
那个人
who killed I-wol.
我无法原谅他
And now, that boy…
而且现在连那个男孩
I will not be able to forgive anyone now.
我似乎都无法原谅了
Then don't.
那就别原谅吧
Be it hatred or resentment. I do not care what it is.
无论憎恨或怨怼 是什么情感都好
Learn to live with it.
借此活下去
As long as it gives you the will to live,
只要那能成为你活下去的力量
it is enough.
那就够了
I will
所有的罪
be responsible for everything.
都让我这个母亲来承担
I will only ask you
但是
to live.
你要活下去
Live…
即便狠下心
even if your heart is burdened.
也要活下去
Mother.
娘
Thank you…
谢谢你
for calling me Mother after everything.
还愿意叫我一声娘
I am…
我真的…
truly grateful.
真的很感谢你
Never forget…
永远别忘了
that you are the Prince.
你是真正的世孙
You are special.
你是个特别的孩子
Your life is the most precious.
比任何人都珍贵
You are the chosen one.
你是被选中的孩子
Mother.
娘
I'm sorry.
对不起
I promised to always protect you.
我答应你要守护你直到最后
But I won't be able to keep that promise.
现在却无法遵守那个约定了
I failed you as your mother and made your life
遇到我这个没用的母亲
harder than it had to be.
你肯定吃了不少苦头
And…
一想到日后
thinking about how you are forced
你依然得在这无止境的苦痛中
to live in this endless pain…
继续活下去
I'm filled with regret.
我就难以阖上眼离开
But I believe in you.
但是我相信你
And that…
如果是你
if there's anyone who can do this, it's you.
势必能战胜一切
Remember what I told you?
我告诉过你吧？
You are…
你是个
very special.
非常特别的孩子
Don't forget that.
别忘了这点
My beautiful…
我美丽的…
daughter.
宝贝女儿
Mother.
娘
The Crown Prince shall now enter.
世子邸下驾到
Your Royal Highness.
邸下
Leave us.
全都退下
I want to be alone with the Crown Princess.
我想跟嫔宫独处片刻
Mother. Please, Mother…
娘
I have one wish, Your Royal Highness.
臣妾有事想拜托您 邸下
Please protect
请一定要保护
the Prince…
世孙
our child.
保护好那孩子
-Your Highness. -Mother…
-娘娘 -娘
Mother…
娘
-Your Highness! -Mother…
-娘娘 -娘
All who are present!
文武百官
Bow down four times!
鞠躬四拜
10 YEARS LATER
（十年后）
Move!
请让道！
Open the door! This is urgent.
快开门！很紧急！
Your Royal Highness, this is Bok-dong.
邸下 小的是福童
Did you get it?
东西弄到手了吗？
Yes. Right here.
是的 在这里
That's silk.
这不是丝绸质地吗？
Yes, Your Royal Highness. I wasn't able to find the one made with cotton.
对 现在找不到棉布抹胸
Please accept it for now.
请先用来应急
I'm sorry, Your Royal Highness.
小的惶恐
When a new maid was cleaning my room,
新来的佣人在打扫小的房间时
she threw out all the cotton covers.
把棉布抹胸全都丢了…
Only do the tasks given to you.
只要做上头吩咐的事就好
Don't do anything that you aren't sure of.
不懂就别轻举妄动
That's the rule here
这就是此处
in my quarters.
东宫殿的规矩
SAMGAEBANG
（三开房）
Do you know how Samgaebang came about?
你们知道三开房设立的缘由吗？
-What? -What? How?
-嗯？ -嗯？是什么缘由？
You see, we have a very important man here.
因为这里有个历史性的重要人物
the state exam at the age of 15!
就取得科举及第 是传说中的男子汉！
He is the legendary man who saved the Vice Minister of Rites of the Ming
他是救回明国礼部侍郎性命
with his miraculous touch.
拥有奇迹般针灸术…
He saved the Vice Minister's life? How?
他救了礼部侍郎一命？是怎么救的？
-How did he do that? -Tell us.
-是怎么救的？ -怎么救的？
Let me.
让个位置给我
This incident took place in the most famous inn
这发生在燕京最知名的
in Yanjing.
客栈中
The Vice Minister played a major role in the Emperor's succession to the throne.
协助明国皇帝登基的 头等功臣礼部侍郎
And food got stuck in his throat…
在用餐时气管…
-My goodness. -Oh, no!
-天啊
…when he was having a meal.
被堵塞所引发的事件
Goodness.
天啊
Sir, what's wrong?
大人 怎么了？
-Are you okay? -Sir, what's wrong?
-怎么回事？怎么了？ -大人 你没事吧？
-Sir! -I think something's stuck in his throat!
-大人！ -他喉咙里有什么东西卡住了！
What are you doing? Come over here!
你快过来！干吗啊？
Someone help!
谁来帮个忙啊！
Hurry! We need some help!
快点！快来帮忙！
What is stuck in his throat?
他的喉咙被什么给…
Who was that?
谁啊？
Get him!
拦住他！
Knock him down!
快砍死他！
Who sent you?
谁派来的？
He survived.
活下来了
Wait.
等等
Are you from Joseon?
您是朝鲜人吗？
Yes.
是的
I'm also from Joseon.
我也是朝鲜人
I don't know how to thank you for this.
我不知道该如何报答你的恩情
Don't thank me. I just did what anyone would do.
这不算什么恩情 我只是做了该做的事罢了
The man you just saved is the Vice Minister of Rites.
大人方才出手相救的是礼部侍郎
You saved an important man's life.
你救了尊贵之人一命
I'm sure the Emperor will give you a grand reward.
皇帝肯定会赐给你莫大的奖赏
Everyone's life is important.
每个人的性命都很可贵
I would have done the same thing even if he turned out
就算刚才倒下的不是礼部侍郎
to be a beggar on the street, not the Vice Minister of Rites.
而是路边的乞丐
Bye.
告辞
"I would have done the same thing."
“我也一样会出手相救”
-He sounds so cool. -How impressive.
-太帅气了！ -好帅气啊！
All right. Let me tell you who this man is now.
好 要说这位是谁呢？
-Who is it? -Who?
-是谁？
-It's… -Who is it?
-就是…
Physician Jung!
郑医员！
Where is Physician Jung?
郑医员在哪里？
Come out now!
大事不好了 郑医员快出来啊
What's wrong?
怎么了？发生什么事了？
His daughter's face is totally ruined. It's a disaster.
他的千金整张脸全走样了 简直惨不忍睹
Physician Jung!
郑医员！
Move!
全都让开！
-Move out of the way. -Step back!
-闪边！ -退开！
-Be quiet. -Gosh.
-安静 -唉唷
Where is the physician?
这里的医员在哪里？
What's going on out here?
怎么这么吵杂？
What?
怎么回事？
-Ji-un.
-大哥 -哥
One out of a hundred faces side effects. It's rare, but it happens.
偶尔在一百个人之中 会有一个人出现这种情况
And I'm the unlucky one?
而我恰巧就是那一个？
Don't worry. It will go away in half a day once you take the medicine I give you.
你放心
Okay. Let me see.
好 让我来看看
Where is the herb for a rash?
出疹子时用的药材在…
-Jil-geum. -Yes.
-质昑 -是
What is it?
什么事？大哥
Go to the herb storage and bring me dried blackish yellow flowers.
你去药材仓库 拿点玄黄色的干燥花过来
Those flowers?
那个啊
We don't have any.
没有了
Of course, we do. Check the third shelf on the right.
怎么会没有？ 你到右边第三个架子上看…
We don't.
没了
We don't?
没了？
Once I get the herbs, I'll give you the medicine right away.
我一拿到药材 就会马上替你开药
You have until the end of today.
今天之内给我弄来
If you fail, I can't promise
否则不只这间三开房
your shop or that girl will be safe.
连她的小命我也不敢保证是否能保全
Is that clear?
听懂了吗？
Damn it!
可恶
Bullseye!
命中！
He sure makes one arrogant Crown Prince.
顶着世子的头衔就装模作样的
Something must be wrong with my arrows.
这为何都射不中啊？
He has his maternal grandfather to thank. Without his grandfather,
若没有尚宪君大监撑腰
The Queen has the King wrapped around her little fingers.
现在殿下拜倒在中殿裙下
So he only adores Prince Jehyeon.
所以只宠爱齐贤大君一个
That explains his need to compensate.
他就只能在那边挣扎
Please watch your tongue, Uncle.
注意你的言辞 叔父
This isn't a private gathering.
在场有很多人在听
What? So what if people hear us?
怎么了？那又怎样？
I wasn't making stuff up anyway.
我又不是无中生有
You know what? I should catch one of those deers,
不然这样好了
so I can get on the good side of Lord Sangheon.
来奉承一下我们尚宪君大监吧
Who knows? He might prefer
比起一个娇滴滴的温室花朵
a man of vigor like me
他有可能会更宠爱我这个
to someone who looks like a delicate flower.
有气魄的大丈夫啊
That hurts!
痛死了！
Who did that?
是谁？
What crazy bastard…
是哪个疯子…
You said you wanted to catch something for my grandfather.
你说要捕些猎物献给我外祖父
The next time you are rash with your words,
你敢再大放厥词的话
I will not let it slide
即便你是叔父
even if you are my uncle.
我也不会原谅你
So you want to play this game?
你想跟我斗到底是吧？
What?
嗯？
What on earth?
什么啊？
He looks like a girl.
他简直就像个女人啊
What?
那是怎么回事？
The Crown Prince has vanished?
邸下消失了？
We must find the Crown Prince before anyone else does.
我们一定要比其他人早一步找到邸下
-Jump. -What?
-快跳 -什么？
A court maid at the royal hunting?
在讲武场的宫女？
She had fair skin, a delicate face, and dark brown hair.
她皮肤白皙 脸只有拳头大小 头发是深褐色
An assassin?
刺客？
An assassin attacked the Crown Prince?
你是说真的有刺客攻击世子吗？
-Hyun? -Why did you spare the man
-王兄 -在讲武场撞见您的那个男子
who saw you at the royal hunting?
您为何饶了他一命？
I must kill him. I will.
当然要除掉 我会杀了他
What is your name?
你叫什么名字？
-My name is Jung Ji-un.
-我叫郑至韵 -微臣是郑至韵
Subtitle translation by: Won-hyang Son
字幕翻译：钟见悦